本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流
更多中日双语字幕，尽在www.kamigami.org 及微博@诸神字幕组
ペシャワール城塞まで　あと少しだというのに
We left a little to Peshawar ...
目的地に近づくほど　待ち伏せする方は容易いわけだ
The closer we get to the goal,
the easier it is to them an ambush.
いくら包囲網が的確であろうと
Wherever they have no waiting ...
Ambush.
待ち伏せか
Caught!
かかったぞ　我が隊の手柄にしろ
Earned a reputation!
Azrail!
アズライール
王太子殿下を守りまいらせよ　ヤシャスィーン
Protect His Highness, the Crown Prince!
Jasasuin!
キシュワード
Кисвард!
アルスラーン殿下
Prince Lions!
よくぞ　ご無事で
Glad to see you whole!
うかつに俺の領地に入ったこと　今　後悔するがいい
And now, you will regret that dared to so blithely invade my land!
退け　退け
Retreat. Retreat!
追う必要はない
Let them go.
お主らの蛮勇を伝え聞かせ　手出しさせないようにするのが得策だ
Let talk about your brave people
and persuaded not to go to us.
それもそうだな
I agree.
ナルサス
Narsus!
ナルサス　先にたどりついていたのか
Narsus goes, you before we arrived.
キシュワードも　よく来てくれた
And Kisvard good that you came.
はっ
Yes!
よくぞ　このような辺境地へおいでくださいました
It's good that you went to this little-known way.
ようこそ　東方国境の要　ペシャワール城へ
Welcome to the castle's eastern border, Peshawar.
Yes.
Narsus, and who is this?
ナルサス　そこの者は
いえ　これは…
Well it...
私はアルフリード
I'm the Alfred.
ナルサスの妻だよ
Female Narsusa.
What?!
なっ
A?!
I wanna know what’s real
I want to know where reality.
You gotta boost up
With forces pull yourself together!
boku no kotoba ja nai kitto kore wa bokutachi no kotoba da
These are not my words, for sure, these words belong to all of us.
日听&翻译
小伍
sora
兰樱
校对
小江
mam
sekaijuu ga hidari te shika nakerya
If only the left hand remained in the world,
片源
Rei
时间轴
钦钦&框框
压制
久嘉
Coolkid
migi te wo kakusu yatsura ni wa naruna
We will not scoundrels who hide right.
kono ao no saki ni nani mo nai
For this azure was nothing there,
kidzuita hi kara sora miagenai
as soon as it is realized at the sky I do not look anymore.
soko nashi numa ni hora soko ga atte
Look, even in the bottomless swamp has a bottom,
ima mo nao kegareyuku kono machi ja
and stands in the city of Bend it.
tada kuuki dake wo suou to shitatte
Even if you try to breathe the air ...
warui mono mo issho ni suikondeshimau
Gets only every poison you in the chest.
itsumo ushinatte
Always I lost ...
itsumo
Always
sat
Fall ...
taerarenai mono nante
It is becoming unbearable.
kono te ni wa tsukuranu you ni to ikitekita bokura no te ni
We live in an attempt to free his hands, but they ...
you are friend, baby, dream
My friend, hold on to the dream.
friend
Friend...
baby, dream
Hold on to a dream ...
kidzukeba mou kokoro ni aishinuku beki mono bakari
No sooner had I seen, in the heart crept into everything that is still valued.
itsumo ushinatte satte
Always I lost ...
itsumo
Always
sat
Fall ...
taerarenai mono sae
Let all unbearable,
mamorezu ni kuyamu dake no hibi ni ikiteitaku wa nai kara
but I do not want to live a loathsome life, to miss the wonderful days.
you are friend, baby, dream
My friend, hold on to the dream.
friend
Friend...
baby, dream
Hold on to a dream ...
motto tsuyokunaru yo
We need to become stronger.
kore wa boku no kotoba janai
These are not my words.
bokura no kotoba
These are our words!
Chapter XIII
ペシャワール城　パルス東方の国境を守る　最強の城塞
Fortress Peshawar.
fortress Peshawar
The mighty fortress, guarding the eastern border Persians.
アトロパテネの会戦の際
In the battle of Atropatena
国境守備のために　出兵をしなかったことが幸いし
they did not send troops to protect the border,
that to our advantage: they are ready to fight.
軍備を維持している
現在　ここが　パルス最後の砦
Who is the last fortress of Parsis
and the greatest combat unit.
そして　最大の戦力である
王子が
This prince!
Prince Lions!
アルスラーン王子
Prince! Prince Arslan!
王子
アルスラーン王子
Otodvinsya little ...
もう少し離れぬか
ナルサス
Narsus that you have happened when we split up?
別行動になっている間　何があった
こんな大事なときに
In such an important moment ...
I...
いや…
ナルサス様…
Mr. Narsus ...
旅は孤独だ
Lonely life on the road.
策士殿とはいえ　魔が差すこともあるだろう
Even Mr. tactics tempted.
こんな粗野な娘でも　乾いた大地で出会えば　恵みの花に見えるだろう
This simple girl, seemingly,
It seems blessed flower, hitting a dry desert.
そうなのか
Really?
弁明してくれ　アルフリード
Explain to them all, the Alfred.
Yes. We are not yet officially married.
Daughter of Commander Zot clan, the Alfred
正式に結婚はしてないんだ
だから　今はただの情婦だけど
So now I'm just a lover.
Mistress ?!
情婦だと
ナルサス様…
Mr. Narsus ...
No! I did not do anything!
違う　俺は何もしておらぬ
襲われていたところを救ってやっただけだ
Just rescued the girl, when she was attacked!
もういい
Pretty.
襲われていた
Attacked?
あの銀仮面が現れた
This appeared in the silver mask.
ここに至るまでの包囲網は　あいつの策だ
It is by his order to attack us on the way here.
王太子殿下
Your Highness!
バフマン
Avalanches!
おお　よくぞ　ご無事で
Captain of Cavalry of the kingdom Pars, Kisvard
Captain of Cavalry of the kingdom Pars, Bahman
Glad to see that you are alive.
世話になるぞ　バフマン　キシュワード
We have to stop you, Bachmann, Kisvard.
パルスはこのペシャワールから　反撃ののろしを上げる
Pars will fight back from here in Peshawar.
みんなの力を貸してくれ
So I ask for your help!
ほう　これは殿下　少し見ない間に　随分とたくましくなられたようだ
Well, Prince,
you become more confident after our last meeting.
はっ
There is!
ペシャワール城にある騎馬２万　歩兵６万挙げて
Twenty thousand horsemen and sixty thousand foot of the fortress of Peshawar
殿下に忠誠を誓わせていただきますぞ
will be honored for the privilege to serve you, Prince.
念入りな包囲網でしたが　まんまと　取り逃がしてしまいましたなぁ
We are well researched neighborhood
but in the end, they managed to get away from us.
まだ終わったわけではない
This is not the end.
Something very bad things.
割に合わんな
What these past few weeks I have achieved?
この数週間　俺ときたら　なんだ
Only the child looked after all the way.
子供のお守りに気をもんでいただけではないか
ナルサスは　この道中　粗野だが　なかなか美しい少女と一緒だった
But during this time Narsus
I found a nice, albeit simple, girl.
まっ　それはいい
Although the right.
面白くないのは
What I do not like,
is that all this time with Mrs. Farangis was not me,
ずっとファランギース殿と一緒だったのが俺ではなく
and this Daryun!
ダリューンだったことだ
Sorry about that, Giev.
それはすまなかった　ギーヴ
殿下
Prince!..
お主の気持ちを察せず　無理をさせてしまった
I did not consider your feelings and too much required.
あっ　いや…
どうしたのです　こんな夜更けに
What are you doing here at this hour?
I wanted to thank you for your help.
ここまでの道中の礼を言いたくてな
本当に世話になった
I owe you.
お気になさるな
No worries.
I was not interested and the system Lyusitanii.
ルシタニアのやり方は　俺も気に入らない
連中にひと泡　吹かせられるなら　まあ　そっちに付いた方がいい
Once there is an opportunity to thwart their plans, then okay, I Stay on this side.
面白いな　ギーヴは
You're interesting, Giev.
Well, thank you.
それは　どうも
And what about what he heard ...
それに　さっきの話　俺は嘆いたわけじゃない
Not that I'm complaining.
美を求める旅の間には　苦難もある
On the way to the pursuit of beauty await difficulties.
何かを追いかけ　求めるのが　人生の面白さというもの
The pursuit of any purpose and makes life more interesting.
決して腐っていたわけではございません
I am not in any way disappointed.
あ…ああ
A-and ...
ナルサス　いる
Narsus, are you here?
お前か
ナルサス　知らない
Not seen Narsusa?
ナルサス様なら　まだここの将軍たちと会議中だ
Mr. Narsus still on the generals' meeting.
あの人　忙しいんだね
He is so busy, it seems.
あっ　そうだ
I know!
じゃあ　ナルサスのこと　いろいろ教えてよ
Then you tell me about Narsusa.
あのさ…
Listen ...
ナルサス様になれなれしくしないでくれないか
Maybe enough so familiarly behave with Mr. Narsusom?
知り合ってから　何日もたってないくせして
You do not know him so long ago.
つきあいの長さと深さは別物よ　そんなこと分からないの
Duration is not related to their depth.
Or you do not know?
ナルサス様の好物も知らないくせに
You do not even know your favorite food Mr Narsusa.
私の料理を不平を言わずに食べてくれたわ
He ate my cooking and did not complain.
Because Mr. Narsus good man!
それはナルサス様がお優しいからさ
お前なんかの料理が口に合うわけないだろ
It is unlikely that your cooking fits his tastes.
お前とは何さ
What do you mean "my" ?!
言っとくけど　私はあんたより年上なのよ
Just so you know, I'm older than you!
Oh, really?
ああ　そうですか
とにかく　ナルサス様の邪魔をしたら　許さないからな
In general, if you interfere with Mr. Narsusu, you'll be sorry.
What ?!
何よ
もう…　なんだよ　あいつ
What's wrong with him ?! And where Narsus ?!
ナルサスの何なんだよ
お主　ナルサス卿のことを好いておるのか
Girl, you're that, like Mr. Narsus?
A?
Yes...
だったら　いけないのかい
And what not?
もし　ナルサス卿を好いておるのなら　妨げにならぬようにすることじゃ
If Mr. Narsus you liked,
you better not get in the way.
あの御仁は　今のところ　一人の女よりも
Who is this man
I am more interested in creating a new realm than in women.
一国を興すことに夢中になっている
しばらくは見守ってやるのもよかろう
Observe until better for his endeavors.
国を興すなんて　意味のないことだよ
Build a new realm of useless.
新しい貴族と奴隷ができるだけさ
Since there will be only the new rich and the slaves.
It is surprising that such a smart man like Narsus, does not understand.
ナルサスほど頭のいい人が　そんなことに気付かないなんてね
そうかもしれぬ
Maybe you are right.
だが　お主のナルサスなら
Only your Narsus can find a way to get rid of this system.
それを克服するような道を見つけるかもしれぬぞ
そういう男だと思えばこそ　彼を好きになったのではないのかな
It is because he is such a person,
you fell in love with him, right?
分かったよ
Okay!
おいしいか
Delicious?
今日は私を助けてくれたからな　お礼だよ
You saved me today, this is my gratitude.
殿下から食事を頂戴するなど　この果報者め
It feeds the Prince,
that's the same as lucky.
キシュワード　そういえば　スルーシはどうした
Kisvard, and what happened to sori?
アズライールとはいつも一緒だったのに
He was always together with Azrael.
そのことにございます
That's the point.
信頼できる部下と共に　王都に潜入させておりました
I sent it to trusted people
to get to the capital.
ですが　ここ数日　連絡がございませぬ
But the word has a few days away.
They were killed?
殺されたのか
Likely.
おそらく
そうか…
Clear.
キシュワード
Kisvard.
私はここペシャワールから挙兵し　王都を奪還する
I will gather here in Peshawar, the army
and the faithful city.
Yes.
はい
Maybe I'm getting ahead of myself, but then,
その後　先走った話かもしれぬが…
新しい国が出来たら　私は奴隷制度を廃止したいと思っている
when we create a new country,
I intend to abolish slavery.
奴隷を解放するとおっしゃいますか
You want to free the slaves ?!
ここまでの道中　私なりに考えたのだ
On the way here I have comprehended this question.
一時の感情だけで　奴隷を解放しても　何にもならない
Passing fancy in the form of exemption does not bring slaves.
だが　きちんと計画を立て　時間をかけて　さまざまな条件を整え
But if you think carefully,
slowly all provide
国を挙げて　それを行えば
and consider them as the country as a whole,
できるのではないだろうか
we can work something out.
殿下のご決心　立派です
I admire your determination.
私個人としては異存はありません
Personally, I have no objection.
ですが　あえて　そのようなことをなされば
But if you decide to take this step,
おそらく　諸侯の大半は殿下のお味方にはなりませんぞ
most likely, the majority of nobility is unlikely to support you.
Narsus also said it.
ナルサスにもそう言われた
だけど　ルシタニア人を追い払って
But as soon as we drive out lyusitaniantsev,
パルスは　全く元どおりというわけにはいかないと思う
it is unlikely we will be able to return to his former life Pars.
If the country does not become better than before,
前よりもこの国がよくなるのでなくては　戦う意味もない
the war was pointless.
もちろん父上がどう思われるかは分からない
Of course, I do not know what to say to my father.
だが　私が父上を助けてさしあげることができれば…
But if I can save her father ...
少しは　私の申し上げることを聞いてくださるだろう
He must listen to at least part of what I say.
挙兵できないというのか
We can not raise an army?
どういうことだ　バフマン殿
What does this mean, Mr. Bachmann ?!
慌てたところで　益はない
Pointless to gather an army in a hurry.
国王陛下の安否さえ　まだ判明せぬ
We still do not know that His Majesty, the King.
Least,
少なくとも　今年のうちに兵を動かすのは　わしは反対じゃ
I am opposed to sending troops before the end of this year.
国内の諸勢力がどう動くか　それを見極めてからにした方がよい
What do we do with those who are now reigns in the kingdom?
We'd better find out first of it all.
アルスラーン殿下を陣頭に立て　パルスの王権を回復させるのは当然のこと
Of course, that Prince Arslan lead the army,
to restore power in Parsa.
我らがそれを行ってこそ　国内の諸勢力も動きはじめるのではありませぬか
Should we not
to act until the move is not done the current government of the kingdom?
バフマン殿はなぜ　それをおためらいになる
Mr Bachmann that is holding you back?
慎重と申すより　やる気がないとしか思えませぬ…
It's not careful.
I can only assume that you have lost a certain ...
Daryun, quite yet.
ダリューン　もうよした方がいい
戦場にあって　一度たりとも敵に後れを取ったことなきバフマン殿なれど
Although Mr. Bachman never won on the battlefield before,
老いとは　むごいもの
all weak in front of old age.
ただ安楽に老後を送れればよいとお考えだろう
He just wants to spend rest of his life in comfort.
How dare you?!
何を言うか　くちばしの黄色いひな鳥めが
You're still a green sucker!
せいぜい　頭を冷やして考え直すのだ
Come, cool your head and think about it again!
Avalanches ...
バフマン…
怒っただけか
You only angered him.
いや　あの老人　もっと食えぬ
No, the old man where trickier.
怒ったふりをして座を外し　追及されるのを避けたのだ
I pretended to be angry and left the room,
to avoid further issues.
ダリューン殿
Mr. Daryun.
バフマン殿のことだが…
As for Mr Bachman ...
実は　アトロパテネの会戦の直前に
The fact is that before the battle of Atropatena,
ヴァフリーズ殿からの手紙が届けられたのだ
he received a letter from Mr. Vahriza.
伯父が手紙を
A letter from his uncle?
俺が知っているのは　そこまでだ
That's all I know.
内容は　検討もつかぬが…
I can not even guess about its content,
それから　バフマン殿はあのように変わられてしまってな
but since Mr. Bachmann has changed, as you saw.
Just before the battle ...
会戦の直前
Darjun.
ダリューン
はっ
Yes.
アルスラーン殿下に忠誠を誓ってくれぬか
You do not prisyagnesh allegiance to the prince for me?
伯父は何を伝えていたのだ
Uncle associated with this?
ナルサス卿には見当はつかぬか
Mr. Narsus, you have a suggestion?
それが分かれば　苦労はせぬよ
If you could see there would be no problems.
俺は千里眼ではない
But I'm not a clairvoyant.
知らねばよかった
I wish I'd never known.
知るべきではなかった
This burden is not for me.
もし何もかも知らずにいられたなら
If it were possible to remain in ignorance,
あの聡明そうな王子に　永遠の忠誠を誓うことができたであろう
I would have sworn eternal allegiance to the prince, who seems wise and prudent.
我が友ヴァフリーズよ
My friend, Vahriz,
you know this truth and yet, despite this,
お主は　このような真実を知って　なお　忠義を尽くしたというのか
He remained faithful to the end?
And yet, strange feeling.
それにしても　奇妙な気分だ
幼い頃は　自分が王子であることすら知らなかった
As a child I did not even know that I am a prince.
宮廷に呼び戻され　暮らすようになって数年
A few years ago I was called back to the palace, where I lived then.
自分は今　王都を離れて　こんな辺境の城で挙兵しようとしている
Now I had to leave the capital,
He is trying to raise an army in the fortress on the edge of korolestva.
だが　簡単な話じゃない
But not all so simple.
確実な秘策でもなければ　王都奪還など　かなわぬ望みだ
To be honest, a plan
it seems to me impossible for capital inning.
In addition, neighboring countries
それに　この機に　隣国だってつけいろうとしているはず
can take advantage of this situation.
父上と母上を救い出し　国を平定するなど
Rescue his father and mother
and bring peace to the kingdom ...
Will I be able to achieve this?
私にできるのだろうか…
そこにいるのは誰だ
Who is there?!
部下も連れず　不用心なことよ
No support. What carelessness.
まさか　このような好機に恵まれるとはな
I did not expect that heaven will bless me so.
銀の仮面
Silver mask ...
That you Lyusitanii strategist was talking about Narsus?
ナルサスが言っていたルシタニアの軍師か
一体　どうやって
How do you?..
I know very well this place.
勝手知ったる場所よ
私ならば　いかようにでも潜入できるわ
I can get here in different ways.
ど…どういう意味だ
What does it mean?!
ア…アンドラゴラスの子　パルスの王太子アルスラーンだ
I Arslan, son Andragorasa, Crown Prince Parsis!
王太子とは僭称するものよな
Crown Prince? Pretenduesh on someone else, right?
貴様は　薄汚い簒奪者の産み落とした惨めな犬ころにすぎぬ身ではないか
You're nothing more than a pathetic puppy
born of vile usurper.
Y-you and he is not better!
そ…そちらも名を名乗れ
何がおかしい
What's so funny?!
Funny though.
おかしいとも
焦がれ焦がれたアンドラゴラスの小せがれが　今目の前にいるのだ
Andragorasa guy, which I've been looking for,
now it stands in front of me!
ただ一人でな
Even one!
この激情を抑えきれぬよ
My rage and asks out!
すぐに殺さぬ
I will not kill you right away.
Sixteen years of torment
１６年の辛苦　一撃で片づけるわけにはいかぬ
dispel one stroke of the sword.
First I cut off your right hand.
まずは　貴様の右手首を斬り落としてくれよう
この次　会ったときは　左手首をもらう
And in our next meeting I deprive you of his left hand.
それでなお生きていたら　右の足首でも頂戴するとしようか
And if after that you'll survive,
Perhaps, then cut off your right foot!
Your crime is already in the fact that you were born son Andragorasa!
アンドラゴラスの子として生を受けたが貴様の罪
Blame your father!
父を恨め
Rapid end do not wait!
楽には終わらせない
What, you can not move?
もう動けないのか
Then, as promised, I will cut off your arm!
では　約束どおり　手首を頂こう
よせ
Abort!
小せがれ…
Detail ...
... You're afraid of fire?
火が怖いのか
アルスラーン殿下
Prince Lions!
Farangis!
ファランギース
What's happening?!
何事だ
Who is it?!
あいつは誰だ
Heck!
へぼ画家
Worthless artist!
I can not constantly ignore it.
二度も三度も聞き捨てならんな
殿下　お下がりください
Prince otoydite!
Stand!
待て
双刀将軍の名に懸けて　城を侵す者は　この手で討ち果たす
I like the general double swords
I will destroy anyone who will penetrate into the fortress!
この男は俺に譲ってもらおう
Better give me this man!
Oh you!..
貴様
You ... damn traitors!
おのれ　逆賊どもが
いま一度　問う
I ask again! Who are you?!
お主は何者だ
俺は先王オスロエスの子
I am the son Osroesa, the previous king.
ヒルメス
Hermes!
なっ
Prince!
殿下
What a spineless, stupid and pathetic man!
なんと甘い　愚かであわれな小せがれよ
バフマンか
Avalanches ...
お懐かしゅうございます　ヒルメス殿下
Long time no see, Prince Hermes.
くっ…くそ
B-devil!
なぜ　邪魔をした
我が友の願いは…
My friend asked ...
アルスラーン殿下をお守りすること…
so I defended Prince Arslan.
I beg...
どうか…お退きください
retreat.
バフマン
Avalanches!
Prince!
殿下
殺してはならん…
Do not kill him!
待て
Stay!
あのお方を殺せば　パルス王家の正当な血が絶えてしまう
If you kill him,
legal race royal family Parsis interrupted it.
何を…
What do you...
バフマン
Avalanches!
Prince...
殿下…
I'm sorry.
申し訳ございません
私は…友の言葉を受け止められず　おびえておりました…
I did not know how to take the words of my friend, and a coward.
アルスラーン殿下
Prince Arslan, please forgive me.
どうか　お許しを…
なぜだ　なぜ　お主が謝る必要がある
For what?
Why do you ask for forgiveness?
よい王とおなりくだされ…
Please be a good king ...
バフマン
Avalanches!
ご報告します
Reporting!
どうした
What?
たった今　シンドゥラの軍勢数万
Now twenty or thirty thousand soldiers Sindurana
pass our border under cover of darkness!
夜の闇に乗じて　国境を突破しつつあるとのこと
What?!
なんだと
ガーデーヴィめに先を越されてなるものか
I will not let this pass me Gadevi.
シンドゥラ国の歴史に不滅の名を刻むのは
In sindoor history will forever be engraved one name ...
この俺よ
My!
yozora wo mau aoki mikadzuki
Azure Moon quietly dancing in the sky,
YakuSub Studio
mabayui sekai wa kumo wo koe
It looks out shining clouds and illuminates the world she is.
translation Mu_Cool
ima kanaderu tabidachi wo
Follow your journey dance
Editorial Mu_Cool
negai wa kanata he nagareyuku
which pave its way of desire.
Making Helge
katachi no nai monogatari ga
When our stories, lost shape,
tsukiakari he shimiwatareba
rastekutsya in hand, like a bright light of the moon,
kimi no naka no takaramono ga
All your precious moments and things
ima kaze ni toketeyuku
solution with the wind blowing in a jiffy.
ashita wa arinomama de habataitemiyou
We will try to reveal their wings tomorrow
itsuka dokoka de kimi wa hoshigatta yo ne
But once in the same place it wanted, right?
kikoerundarou hora kagayaiteta ano hi no yume
Can you hear now? Out your brightest dream speaks to you.
yozora wo mau aoki mikadzuki
Azure Moon quietly dancing in the sky,
mabayui sekai wa kumo wo koe
It looks out shining clouds and illuminates the world she is.
ima kanaderu tabidachi wo
Follow your journey dance
negai wa kanata he
which pave the way to desire.
aa kono yume ga hateru made
Oh, and as a result of these desires materialize!
パルス暦３２０年　王都陥落
The era of Parsis, 320 a year, the capital fell.
故国奪還のため　王太子アルスラーンの長い戦いが始まった
Prince Arslan long battle for the return of the kingdom began.
次回　追憶の章　奪還の刃
The next time, the head of the last:. "Blade exempting the Kingdom"
Chapter last
少年は　そして王となる
And so the guy would be King.